If you want to make more money
and get more clients
and do so without burning out
or having to hang out in Facebook groups,
do cold outreach to random
people on the internet,
or sit on sales calls for 45 minutes for
people to get to
the end and say,
"Let me think about it," I've created a
weird system that just
doesn't stop working. Now,
it's never a professional thing to talk
shit
about your competitors online,
but the majority of them are one-trick
ponies.
They've had one business that's done very
well, and then because of that,
they're positive
that their system of cold DMs
or whatever it is they're telling
you to do, they think that is the way
that it works.
I, by complete accident,
ended up having an eight-figure fitness
business,
an eight-figure drinks business
or nootropics business, which some news
is going to
come out about in the next few weeks
regarding that valuation, a seven-figure
business-to-business business, which
is what we have now, a seven-figure books
business, and then from my events,
live tours, et cetera,
is another seven-figure business.
It's worth noting
that just because you say you have a
seven-figure business
doesn't mean you've got £1 million in your
account from that business.
It just means the revenue of
that business is seven figures.
So the point isn't
that I've got millions in the bank,
it's that this system just
keeps working. And it could be luck,
but I'm pretty sure it's the system.
And if at any point in this video you're
starting to resonate with the things that
I'm saying,
there's a link in the description where I
can give you 30 more bits of
business advice that will help you grow
for free.
I hate making content about myself,
but there's some lessons from my own
journey
that you can apply to where you're at
that's going to help you.
The only time I'll ever talk about myself
is if it's to help you.
Lesson number one, LoveFilm.
You've never heard of LoveFilm, have you?
This would've been a long time ago,
Declan.
Let me save the images here.
I'm going to leave a photo of it here for
some people,
which may bring them nostalgia.
So you had Blockbuster in Australia?
Yeah, like renting films. So in the UK,
there was a company called LoveFilm.
And LoveFilm pretty much arrived on the
scene before Netflix and said, "Instead of
going to Blockbuster
and renting a film
and paying whatever it was to do it, for a
certain fixed price,
you can have unlimited rentals, Declan,
every month,
but you're going to get one at a time." So
they post you the DVD.
When you finish, you send it back.
So the lazier or inactive you are with it,
the
less films you could watch. But
if you were someone that was on top of it,
you
could watch four, five,
six films in a month,
and it would cost less than going to
Blockbuster. I sold that. Now, it
was commission only, £7
a sale, so like $14. However,
if I hit 10 sales in a
day, that commission went up to £9,
which meant £90
for a day's work. Where was I working?
Shopping centers.
So you know the people
that come up to you in the shopping
centers, they're all in
uniform, and they've got the lanyard,
and they try and stop you? That was me.
So I would be working in Swindon,
Gloucester, any shopping center
there was, Reading,
stopping people in their tracks,
trying to sell them something
that they never really heard of.
And here is the number one thing I learned
from
that: rejection. Every single day, maybe
99% of people that I would interact with
would reject me.
They would say, "No, thanks.
Not interested." Or they would do this
or pretend you're just not there.
They would just keep their eyes on where
they're
going,
and they'd just walk straight past you.
So even at the age of maybe 18, 17,
when I was doing this,
got very comfortable
with rejection. Also, another thing,
side note, tangent, was not to ask
closed questions. So if you
were to say to someone, "Hey,
are you having a
good day?" They could just say, "Yes,"
and carry on walking.
But if you were to say to someone
something like an open question,
"Where do you
currently rent your films from?" They'd
go, "Blockbuster." I'd go, "That's amazing
because LoveFilm is actually going to
compete and save you money from doing so.
Let me tell you a little bit about it."
Or I would sometimes say to people, "How
much a week do you spend at Blockbuster?"
That'd be the first thing I say to them.
They go, "£9." I go, "Wow. This
is LoveFilm.
You're going to be able to get more
movies, it's going to cost you less,
and you
won't even have to go to the store.
Can I give you 30 seconds to tell you a
little
bit more about it?" They go, "Oh,
go on then." So even the way
that you propose
questions. Another sales tactic
that I learned, Declan,
here's one for you, which
actually will get me onto the second part.
Are older people more likely to be fooled
by the sales tactics? Not really.
It's just a way of having a conversation
with people.
By you letting them answer something yes
or no, you're just giving them an
opportunity to. Even hooks in content,
you're positioning a question to
someone. Do you want to lose fat? Yes.
Scroll past.
Video gone. Whereas if your hook
was to be like, "Imagine there
was a simple
formula that means you could lose more
weight without more trips to the gym,
without eating less calories, and
that one formula was walking.
But to find out how walking can benefit
your cardiovascular regime,
we need to look
at three things." You just take them on a
journey.
This isn't like NLP or anything like that.
But maybe, actually, you could be right.
Maybe, what do you think young people
are less susceptible to? Rebel Sport,
yeah.
It was always the old fuckers I
was able to sell, he says.
Lucky you're on that side of the camera
and they don't know what you look like.
But I'll tell you, there's another thing,
right?
So I did sales training at another company
that I worked for, which we're going to
get onto in a second. In that,
they sat us opposite someone else,
and they said,
"You've got a minute to find out what the
person sat opposite,
what their house looks like,
and you're going to have to draw it in
real time." So
I was sat there opposite someone,
and they were like,
"Do you live in a house?
Is it semi-detached?" "It's detached."
They were like, "Yeah, it's detached." So
I'd be there, and I'd start drawing it,
and I'd be like, "Okay, how many
windows does it have?" And they'd say,
"It's got three windows." I'd be like,
"Okay, cool." And the time's ticking.
And then I'd be like,
"Is your door on the left side
or the right side?" They'd
say,
"It's on the right side." I'd be like,
"Oh, fuck." So I quickly put this here,
and then I'd draw the door and put
that there.
"What type of roof does it have?"
And whatever. Then the time was up.
Maybe there was a little tree in the back
garden or whatever.
And we all compared different notes,
and we took it in turns to draw each
other's
houses, whatever.
And then the guy at the end said,
"How many of you just asked the
person opposite you to describe what their
house looked like?" And we were like,
"What?" None of us did that.
We all asked questions really bit by bit,
trying to figure out what their house
looked like.
And basically, what this means is
when you do sales consults as a personal
trainer,
personal trainer's like,
"So do you want to lose fat?
How much do you want to lose?
How many times a week do you want to
train?
What type of train?"
When really you should sit there and go,
"What do you want
this regime to look like?
What do your goals look like?" You give
really broad
things.
Explain to me how a perfect structure of
training and diet would look like,
and then you just let them talk
And then they go,
"I'd like to train three to four
times a week.
I would like my workouts to be 45 minutes.
I would like to not have to count
calories." They paint the perfect picture
for
you, then you construct. So after
that client has told you exactly what they
want,
you go, "Cool. We train four times a week.
We do 45 minutes per session,
and we're going to look at some kind of
rigid nutritional strategy
that doesn't involve you having to count
calories." And
they go, "Do you know what?
That sounds bloody brilliant." Of course
it does.
They just told you beforehand. So
when I do calls with people helping their
business, I just sit there and go,
"What do you need help with?"
And they'll just
tell me everything. Saves time.
Going back to that point about rejection.
Very early on,
I got to become comfortable with people
just saying, "No,
thanks." And I got to realize
that I could make 90 pounds a day,
which to me at the
time was huge amounts of money,
with almost everyone ignoring
me and telling me to fuck off. And
when I realized that I could make a living
with
the vast majority of people not being even
remotely interested in what I was doing,
it gave me a weird amount of hope. Now,
a lot of you working online
face rejection every day,
you just don't see it.
And because you don't see rejection,
you don't think what you're doing
is working.
However, a lot of the time,
it actually boils down to the very next
point, which is
numbers. So the second job I worked at
was for a company called npower
that did gas
and electricity. And ultimately,
the weird thing is,
I still don't understand this,
all of our houses get electricity from the
same wire, gets gas from the same pipes,
but yet you pay a provider. And
if you switch providers,
same gas comes through
same pipe.
I don't understand how it works.
But I was working for npower in their
door-to-door sales department.
And when I interviewed for the job,
"James,
so what do you think you can add to the
team?" I go, "Well,
I come from shopping centers,
selling love film." They're like,
"Oh,
the little DVDs in the sleeves." It's
like, "Yeah." They're like, "You're in."
Because if you can sell in shopping
centers, door-to-door
is going to be easier.
Because in shopping centers,
you've got to stop someone on the move.
Knocking on someone's door,
they've just got to open the door
and you pitch.
I've told this a few times on this
channel, but long story short,
I tried to quit
my job because I was hating it, and it
was freezing, and I was in Gloucester.
And people in the GL1 postcode aren't the
most receptive to you
interrupting the Jeremy Kyle Show in the
morning.
Do you know what the Jeremy Kyle Show is?
Top Gear.
No, that's Jeremy Clarkson,
not Jeremy Kyle. Fucking hell.
Showing your age.
And I remember trying to quit.
Called my manager.
He goes, "James,
let me pull over." Gets his laptop out.
He goes, "Mate,
you make one sale every 100 doors." I
was like, "Right." He's like,
"How many sales do you need for today?" I
was like, "Two." He's like, "Knock on 200
fucking more doors." Boom. Done.
I came to realize that there is
always a certain amount of numbers that's
going to save you, in the sense that no
matter how ugly you are,
you talk to a certain amount of girls,
you're getting a
number.
No matter how annoying your sales pitch
is selling a gas and electric,
if you knock on enough doors,
you're going to find a disgruntled British
Gas
customer. And two weeks into my job,
British Gas put their prices up, and there
actually were quite a lot of disgruntled
people.
But without knocking on enough doors,
I just would not find enough people that
were ready to change their provider for
gas, electric, whatever.
So when you take lesson one
and lesson two,
being comfortable with rejection of
people not being interested,
because you can have the best thing in the
world, some
people just don't care.
The second thing is, a lot of the time,
there is just
not enough numbers of people
that you've reached yet,
whether it's your following,
whether it's your email list,
whether it's visits to your landing page,
which we'll
get onto in a second.
Some people will send 100 people to their
landing page.
No one will buy, and they'll go,
"My landing page doesn't work," or,
"I've sent the
wrong people," when the truth
is they just don't appreciate the majority
of people
aren't interested,
and you've not sent enough traffic at this
stage yet.
And why these lessons are so important,
we'll get onto in a second.
Lesson number three
was at a company called Clarify that
was in Reading.
Well, technically it was in Theale.
And my job there was to make 100 phone
calls a day.
And I hated it. Hated it. It was awful.
Now, this is where you
and I could be different.
You might love sales calls, phone calls,
whatever. I hate them.
I don't enjoy them at all.
And I think it's probably stemming
from having quite bad ADHD. Now,
I don't even know if ADHD's
real. Yes, I got a clinical diagnosis.
Yes, I've been cleared to take meds,
and I'm not interested.
But my brain just doesn't work right as
per everyone else's.
One,
I could just rift videos like this all the
time.
I'm very creative, very impulsive.
The impulsivity thing kills me.
I've just got another idea for a video.
That's ADHD there as well going.
Don't let me forget, coffee machine.
Got a whole video out of this.
Super impulsive. Dopamine junkie.
In fact,
one of the main reasons I got into social
media was because every time you
post, you get a score allocated to that.
So then when a video does better than
another video, dopamine like [groans] .
When doing email marketing campaign,
and your click-through rate is like the
highest it's ever been [groans] .
Putting out a YouTube video like today
and seeing
my average view duration go up,
like [groans] .
That's where I get dopamine.
So you know those people
that make a YouTube video over the course
of
three weeks to put it out
and get millions of views? No.
I want it edited today, Declan.
I want it to go out today so I can be
disappointed
with the analytics so we can do it again
tomorrow. That's how I like it.
I like my dopamine on the daily.
It's why every idea I have
comes from in the shower, because
when it comes to the human mind,
you have system
one and system two. I'm pretty sure,
can't remember this,
from "Thinking Fast and
Slow," Daniel Kahneman book.
There's one side of our brain that's
cognitively
having to think hard,
and then we have the other side that
is automated.
So for instance, I believe that
when you learn to drive, Declan,
system one is you
going, "Okay, clutch in, first gear,
lift the clutch, press the
accelerator,
indicator." That's system one.
But then if you do it for long enough,
it goes into system two,
becomes automated.
Now you just drive. Same with editing.
When you guys start, there's a lesson.
When you start editing, you're like,
"Okay, cut key, Command + B, Command + B.
Okay, move that. Delete.
Ripple delete." It's very cognitively
taxing.
But if you do enough things from system
one, they very soon become system
two. So again, before you know it,
it's like "Minority Report." You're in the
edit,
just chopping it up,
it's moving it around. Takes time.
For me,
I need to go do something like get in the
shower so my system
one part of my brain can relax.
The very ADHD part of my brain
is screaming all
the time. Boom, boom, boom. Ideas. This,
that.
Random impulsivity to buy things, there.
But when I go have a shower
and I can't be impulsive, my mind relaxes,
and I get a
great idea for a video.
So I need to put myself in an environment
sometimes where I
can be more creative.
I also have a very inverted relationship
with
drugs. Often,
I can do a line of cocaine
and go straight to sleep, and can have
600, 700 milligrams of caffeine,
straight to sleep, relax, fine.
Even MDMA kind of relaxes me a little bit.
Because of that,
I hate phone calls because I'm not even
listening when you-I'm on
the phone.
I'm just pretending to play the part of,
"Oh, that's interesting." It's
not interesting. I hate this.
I want to go. I don't want to be here.
So I had to create a system where I could
take the three pillars of lesson one,
lesson two, lesson three,
where I could deal with rejection,
get enough
people's numbers
that I could get the sale,
and do it without having to do
any types of sales calls,
or any outbound thing.
Because if you take on a sales call,
you're just opening yourself up to more
rejection,
and then there's only so much rejection
you can take before it makes you
not want to chase any more numbers.
And then if you don't chase any more
numbers,
the self-perpetuating cycle of hate
in your life continues. Now,
the system I've developed has morphed
throughout the
years.
So the first system I had to create
was for personal training.
Now, I took the experience
that I had before from sales calls,
door-to-door sales, whatever it was.
I knew that if I spoke to enough people on
the gym floor, that someone would be
interested.
It had to be less than what it
was in shopping centers or knocking
on doors.
People are in a gym for a reason.
Personal trainers
are in a gym for a reason.
People are in the gym because they're fat,
they're unfit, they've got no muscle,
they don't know how to train.
Personal trainers
are in the gym because they've
probably gone through their own shit
and they know how to get leaner and more
muscular, whatever. There's the synergy.
So I knew I talked to 15 people,
they would all tell me to piss off,
but then
the 16th one, they would say, "Okay, yeah,
I've actually looked into getting
personal training," or whatever.
And I knew that there
was a success rate there of 16 people you
talk to,
one person would be interested.
The next move from
that would be getting that one
person to come in and sit down
and just talk about their goals.
And the first thing I would say to them,
as we said before, is, "What is it you're
looking to do?" That person would then
paint perfect world of what it looked
like.
I would then say to them, "Cool,
here's the offer of what I recommend." I
would add
a money-back guarantee.
And now the money-back guarantee wasn't so
much for them,
it was for me. Yeah, cool. Yeah,
protect their investment, blah, blah,
blah.
You've heard it before.
But there's nothing better than me turning
around and
saying to someone, "Oh, Declan,
what's that?
You want to train three to four times a
week.
You only want to do 45-minute sessions.
I'll get this working.
You don't want to count calories.
I'm going to create a system
and a structure
that's going to work for you.
I'll tell you what, Declan,
if after three months you
haven't significantly grown in strength,
muscle mass, and lost the fat you want to,
you let me know,
I'll refund you in full." They think
that's there to protect them.
And in some respects, it is. But really,
it's there to protect me.
Because they've listened to everything,
it's starting to sound too good to be
true.
They're starting to think, "Oh,
this guy's just a good salesman.
This person's just got a good chat." Then
when you hit them with the money-back
guarantee,
it's actually given me an outro to the
offer to solidify it so they
can trust me. Now, the beauty of this is,
it either works or it doesn't.
And if it works, I'm safe. And
if it doesn't,
they deserve their money back anyway.
Now,
there's a second part of this PT structure
that's really important.
Any of you operating a calendar.
I don't operate a calendar.
I've never really operated a calendar.
If you put one thing in my calendar,
it ruins my day. I actually get paralysis.
You put something in at 2:00 PM,
don't expect anything from me beforehand.
Some other people say that's an ADHD
thing.
Then I just literally sit around all day
petrified that I'm going to forget
whatever it was that was in the calendar,
and I don't get anything done.
You want to ruin my day,
put something in my diary.
So let's imagine for a second,
you look through your diary and Xs
represent clients
that you found walking the floor,
and Os represents
clients that came in online through social
media.
Sometimes we like to tell ourselves a
story that we're killing it on social
media,
or we're killing it in email marketing,
or our business is killing it,
whatever. Sometimes it
is important to look at your existing
diary and start giving attribution to your
clients to where they came
from. Because looking at this diary,
you would say, "Hey,
I think it's great that
you're trying to build out your social
media.
I think it's great
that you're building your email marketing
list." But by looking
at this, I would say,
"If you need five more clients,
you should go to the gym
floor,
not to Facebook." Sometimes our beliefs of
our systems for sales
and marketing aren't quite as good as what
we tell ourselves.
So we have a system in place that works,
but we must also look at our
system to determine where these clients
come from.
And whenever we do go onto a big push from
new clients,
often you're better off allocating
that energy to stuff that you know
is working.
So this worked well for me.
And I even got to the point where I would
do seven or
eight PT sessions in a day. Then as I
was leaving the gym, I'd go, "James,
just go
talk to 10 people." And I would hope,
I'd be like, "Please,
just let me go talk to
10 people.
Let them all say they're not interested."
I quickly go around the PT
floor. "Hey, you all right?
Anything you need? Yeah, cool.
See you later." I'd go to the next person,
then boom.
One son of a bitch would go, "Yeah.
How much is PT?" I'd go, "Oh my God,
I'm just
trying to go home, you savage."
And then I'd end up going into the same
system, sit
them down for a consult, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
Now,
this accidentally became a massive online
PT
empire. I'll explain to you how.
Long story short, a lad called Cliff DM'd
me and said, "Hey,
mate." He actually emailed me.
"I want to work with you as a coach.
I live in Dubai." I go, "Mate, I'm in
Bracknell. No way this
is going to work." He goes,
"Train me from Bracknell.
Don't care how it looks.
There's just loads of bellends online,
and I'd like you to
do my program." So I had to actually now
create something just for Cliff.
I was like, "Hey, mate.
How about I write your training program?"
I think I gave
him macros.
"And I'll check in with you." Now,
side tangent.
A lot of you personal trainers love giving
people an hourly check-in once a week.
I think you're running yourself into the
ground doing them.
I don't think your clients really care.
I've never done a check-in.
Never done a check-in in my life.
What I used to do was just send them daily
WhatsApp, and it would be like, "Hey,
Cliff, how was today?" "Yeah,
haven't trained
yet.
I'll let you know how it goes." "Cool."
Next day.
"How was the workout?" "Yeah,
didn't really vibe with the front foot
elevated split
squats." "Cool.
Do you want me to change them to rear foot
elevated?" "Yeah."
"Great." But I suddenly realized
that in this second system here,
I'd acquired
Cliff as a client without doing any
consult.
He had just seen what I
was putting out on social media.
Cliff had seen it, and before you know it,
he was ready to buy.
I thought, "Wow, this is amazing.
How can I create a system that
can get clients that are amazing,
like Cliff?
One,
don't have to talk to them on the phone.
Two,
don't even have to meet them for a
consult.
Three, I'm just WhatsApping a guy,
sending his program and doing macros.
I'm not having to give him half the energy
I would have to give someone in person,
and I'm getting paid for it." So for
system two, social media, I would actually
drive people.
I bet you've never heard of WordPress,
have you? Know WordPress?
Oh, you know WordPress. Yeah,
a website builder.
That's what we had back in the day before
videos.
So then I would write blogs,
and my call to action at the end was,
"And if you enjoyed this blog,
you would love my emails." So I started
running email marketing campaigns In 2016.
Then shortly after that, video came out,
and then video started
dominating. And then before you know it,
WordPress kind of died a little death.
Call to actions, whether it
was click link in bio or another one,
chatbots.
And again,
chatbots have been around since about
2018, 2019, but they're becoming
more popular now since they partnered with
Meta.
Now I was growing an email list,
and I will be honest,
before I set sail to go to
Australia, I sent one email out that said,
"If you're interested in
doing online coaching with me,
reply to this email." From that email in
2016, I got 16 clients,
they paid me £55 a week.
What is 16 times 55?
That put me on £880 a week as a
backpacker. What is 880 times 52?
45,760. Sick. So just from that one email,
I
put myself on a salary of 45K a year just
asking people if they wanted to train
online. However, there
was then an issue
that people would have to come, say
they're interested on email, then
that consult became email exchanges
between
people.
Now my online coaching business changed to
the point that instead of
charging people £55 a week,
we started charging them £40 a month.
And that's where the system really became
clean. I would use social media.
I would get emails,
and then the traffic from the emails would
go to something
called a landing page. Now
if you want a visual representation of
what my landing
page looks like,
there's a link in the description where it
says, "If you want to
know what I do," blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
You can go look at my landing page,
and you can look and copy the flow of
exactly
how I've put it there.
Now remember the lessons we spoke about
before.
Let's imagine there
is 100,000 people on your social media.
The next stage you would want about 20,000
of those emails.
I think as a golden rule, 20%
is a sweet amount.
Now keep in mind, that means
that 80,000 people, 8 out of 10 people,
don't want to give you their emails.
There's the rejection.
However, with 20,000, there
is going to be enough people in there,
lesson two,
numbers of people interested in doing your
stuff.
Then out of that,
let's imagine you get a 50% open rate.
That takes you to 10,000.
Then out of that, even if you get a 3%
click-through rate, then even if you
were only to get 1% of people from the
click-through rate to do business,
you get three clients.
That's three clients from every email.
So if you send an email every day,
you're looking at 21 clients per week.
Really rough fag packet maths. You get it.
So I'd created a system here
that worked for my fitness business,
got over 100,000
people through the door of the training
app.
And I never had to do a consult,
never had to sit on a sales call,
never had to go
into a shopping center to get people to
join.
Which brings us into the third part of
this.
I thought for a really long time
that I just created a system
that worked for my
business.
I didn't think you could really rinse
and repeat it.
So we start off with the book.
Already had the social media following,
already had
the emails.
So I asked politely in an email
if people would pre-order the book
as a call to action.
"Sunday Times" number one bestseller.
That's the highest accolade.
A lot of people out there, they're like,
"Oh, I'm a
'Sunday Times' bestselling author."
Were you number one? Didn't think so.
Shut up.
Get back in the box. So then
if we needed more orders for the book,
we just
needed more emails.
If we needed more emails,
we just did more posts on social
media that would drive people to it.
It's like surely it can't be this simple.
Not only did I get the best accolade you
can as an author, I've done it three
times. Number one bestselling author.
And I'm probably going to do it several
more times.
Was it my marketing ability
or my writing ability?
Well, mate, if you read them,
you realize it's obviously from my
marketing.
Same way no one is getting laid because of
the size of their penis.
Because the size of your penis has nothing
to do with your ability to get laid.
They only find out about the size of your
penis once they're at your house.
So what I'm saying
is no one knows how good your book is
or bad it is until they've
bought it.
You don't get the "Sunday Times" accolade
for having a good book.
You get it for selling a lot of books.
The whole system is rigged on your
marketing.
That's the whole fucked thing about it.
Now, I put a lot of effort into my books.
I'm confident to say they're pretty good,
but they're not going to be as good as
some people that just do this all day in,
day out. I'm busy, mate.
So absolutely to your point,
it wasn't my ability to write a book
that got me that
accolade.
It was the very system I'm talking about
today.
Now, it was a bit of a whim. I was like,
"Wow, I've created this system for sales
online. Let's apply it to a book." Boom.
Does well.
Then what we did, which was pretty clever,
is we created a whole event system off
the back of the book.
So we had book tours, 3,500 people.
Hammersmith Apollo, Sydney Opera House,
sold out.
I'll be honest with you, in 2021,
because they lowered VAT
and stuff coming out of
the pandemic,
we made more money from the tour than we
did from the book, which is
wild. Hammersmith Apollo
was over £100,000 for the night.
For the night.
So surely you couldn't rinse
and repeat this again.
Again, social media.
We created new brand pages. Fair enough.
But ultimately, Chris Williamson,
James Smith.
The first thing we did on launch,
he emails.
Where did the email send people?
Landing page. And any of you that
are on LinkedIn,
probably over the next few
weeks,
you're going to see the big news
that we have surrounding that as to why
it's now valued at eight figures.
Little flex. Nothing has changed.
The system is the same.
We leverage social media to get people on
our email list,
or they're already on our email list from
previous campaigns.
This is why there's the importance of
emails.
Working with a fitness business this
morning in Ireland, and they're saying,
"James, are you sure
that we need to be putting our focus
onto emails?" And I said, "Yes,
mate." Because
it's not even the thing you're selling.
It's the ability that
if you use this system correctly
and use social media to get
people's contact information,
when you go to sell them something
different, you can
bypass the whole first part of the system
and send them straight to a landing page.
Now, what if they're not interested?
Well, good news is,
as we've learnt from everything before,
the majority of people
aren't interested in the majority of
things you sell.
But if you have that one person
that answers the door in every 100
doors, you're going to make your sale
and keep your boss happy.
If you're going to put up with enough
rejection on social media to eventually
get
through to the point
that you find an audience of people
that actually care about
the stuff you're doing,
you're going to get the sale.
And if you can appreciate the dwindling
effect, Chris and I have got
millions of followers on social media,
but then we've only got hundreds of
thousands on our email list,
but then we only need tens of thousands of
people as
new tonic customers for us to do very,
very, very well.
Now I'm going to put a company on blast.
Let's call this a case study.
Paperboy is an email marketing company,
and everything I'm about to say is in my
honest personal opinion. They message me,
go, "Hey, James.
We work with the likes of Chris
Williamson, Sahil Bloom," blah, blah,
blah.
I go, "Cool. That's sick." They go,
"We'd like to grow your email list." I
said,
"Sick." I go,
"Tell me how you're going to do it.
I'll send you the money." They go,
"Do you want to jump on a call?" I said,
"No." I
said, "Mate,
I know how important email marketing is.
I'm a big fan of email marketing.
Just tell me how you're going to do it
and I'll
pay you." Sends me an 11-minute Loom
video.
I get one minute in, I go, "Bro,
maybe I'm real stupid.
I don't know what the hell you're on
about.
Just tell me how you're going to do it."
Comes back. Let me find it.
Here it is, Declan. He then says to me,
"Giving him a monthly budget of
$10,000,
he can get me 404,000 subscribers over 12
months,
$1.2 million in potential revenue,
and a 727% return on
investment." I said, "Hey, mate, how
are you getting this information?" He
didn't
even know any of the businesses
that I had.
I said, "Mate, just tell me now what it
is you're doing, or I'm not going to talk
to you again." He goes, "Mate,
we're going to do paid social advertising
on
Instagram and Facebook." I was like,
"Cool.
I already do that." Affiliate programs.
You ready for this?
You pay other newsletters per qualified
subscriber, and
only after three to four weeks once you've
confirmed quality.
Then organic swap groups will pay you with
newsletters like Chris Williamson, Sahil
Bloom, to co-promote. His best idea,
granted that for
10 years I've been using social media to
get emails, to send people to a landing
page. 10 years I've been doing that,
multiple businesses.
He then goes,
"You can do a newsletter swap where I say
to my list,
'Hey,
go join Chris Williamson's email
newsletter,' and
Chris goes and says to people, 'Hey,
why don't you join James's?'" That was his
best strategy for getting emails.
$10,000 a month.
Now,
for those of you interested in how to get
emails, you give something of value.
Because me begging you to join someone
else's email list doesn't give them any
value. The only reason content works is
if it has value.
Now, the value should not be an e-book,
because guess what? No one's finishing it.
And if they don't finish your e-book,
they're not going to join your program
because they're going to go, "Jesus,
I couldn't even get through a PDF.
How am I going to get through their
program?" One thing I love at the moment
is
something called an autoresponder.
Again, to copy the autoresponder,
link in this,
"30 Ways in 30 Days." What I'm
going to do is hit you with a little
nugget of wisdom that takes 45 seconds to
read, one a day for 30 days.
Between days 19 and 21,
you usually sign up.
Even if you're not interested in what I
sell, check that out so you can copy it.
Now, the reason I say that as well
is a lot of people then go onto it to copy
it,
and then end up buying because it's so
powerful.
10 grand a month, paperboy, and that
was your best strategy that you
had. Ridiculous.
So I'm walking with my manager the other
day.
We're walking through London,
and I said to him, "Mate, am I an idiot?
Am I a fraud?
Because my system seems to be so much
simpler than all the others
that people are selling.
It's even so simple that sometimes I feel
fraudulent telling people about it." He
says to me, "No, mate." He does events,
festivals, anything. Fisher in Dubai,
Defected, did 50 Cent's
last tour. He goes, "Mate,
we run paid ads because they don't have
social media to
do so to get email addresses." He goes,
"From the amount of email addresses we
have,
we know exactly how many tickets we're
going to sell.
We know how successful an event
is going to be based on how many emails we
have in the lead-up to it. Then
when we go and sell, we know
that a certain
percentage of those people
are going to buy." Done.
The system that's worked for me.
Obviously,
I say social media because I've managed
to grow social media accounts,
but let's look at it this way.
Social media, you grow by making good,
engaging content that
helps people.
You can then run paid ads
and initiatives on top,
but if you are not good at making organic
content, your paid content is going to
fall flat on its face.
Get better at this first.
This will get a lot easier.
Both of these things should do one thing,
and
that is to get someone's email
or their data.
If anyone tells you
that anything you should be doing on
social media has anything
to do apart from this, they are lying.
By me telling you in this video to get the
30-day autoresponder, I'm going to get
your emails. Through you going
and checking out my landing page,
I'm then going to
be able to attribute paid ads to retarget
you.
And then eventually you might buy either
the main products I'm selling or one of
the smaller satellite courses that I sell.
And the reason they're so cheap
is because then I get your email,
and then I get
your data. Then ultimately,
every single thing
is going to send you to a landing
page, which in essence
is a digital means of me doing the
consult.
It's a digital means of me doing the sales
call.
It's a digital means for you to find out
what it is, why you need it, what you get,
how much it costs, and how you can buy.
This just continues to keep working,
and there is no reason that
this can't work for any business
that you're in, whether personal training,
whether
an accountancy firm,
whether a jujitsu tournament,
whatever it is.
Either I'm the luckiest person that's ever
lived, or this actually
works, and anyone
that tries to overcomplicate this
is just doing so so that
you buy into their system.
I say this before, I say it again.
Let's look at a product like Eight Sleep.
My mattress topper
was $7,000 because I got the Pod 4
Ultra Pro, whatever it is. For that,
you go on the website.
First thing they do
is they get your email address.
When they get your email address,
they hammer you until you buy.
That product is 7,000 Australian dollars,
or like 3,500
US.
What do they do to put the final nail in
the coffin?
They hit you with a money-back guarantee
because they know the product's good
enough that when you lay on it,
you're going to end up keeping it.
So suddenly me saying that,
you're thinking, "Wow,
can I really trust you, James?
Can I trust Alex Hormozi?
Can I trust Simon Squibb?
Or are you all just trying to dress up the
very same system in a different way?"
Well,
the only way you're really going to know
how fraudulent we are and if the
things we say are true
is to look at the dark truth behind why
we're all saying
the very same thing.
The only way you're going to understand
that is to watch this
video that I put together for you a few
days ago